[{"answer": "Well, he was a pioneer, in the -- you know, in the early days of television, with \"American Bandstand,\" he revolutionized music on television.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 39, "question": "Put him in context, historical context, how important was Dick Clark, do you think?", "qSentId": 38}, {"answer": "Amazing.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 54, "question": "Isn't that amazing?", "qSentId": 53}, {"answer": "He was a great generalist.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 64, "question": "What was the secret ingredient that he had?", "qSentId": 63}, {"answer": "Well, there would have been no career without Dick Clark.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 83, "question": "What was Dick's importance to you, your career and your life?", "qSentId": 82}, {"answer": "RANCIS: Well, it was really up until -- I think I saw him a year and a half ago, I went to visit Kari and Dick in Malibu, their home.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 95, "question": "Do you think in the end that he realized that wasn't what was important to his life?", "qSentId": 94}, {"answer": "It was the show that everybody wanted to be on because it presented their talent.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 112, "question": "What was the importance of \"American Bandstand\" to any young musical act in America?", "qSentId": 111}, {"answer": "I have to think of it -- Steve Jobs, interviewed him early on, he had it.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 194, "question": "How many people -- of all the people that you ever interviewed had that distinctive, gut feel for what the majority of Americans would love to see or hear?", "qSentId": 193}, {"answer": "Actually, Piers, I got an experience that \"Donny and Marie Show.\"", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 227, "question": "Was that your experience?", "qSentId": 226}, {"answer": "Well, I got to tell you, I think only Dick Clark could have talked me into doing that, because, you know, twice in my life my knees have knocked, and that was one of them.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 249, "question": "What did he do, how was he in that persuasive mode?", "qSentId": 248}, {"answer": "He was an every man.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 303, "question": "What was it about him that enabled him to persuade people they had the confidence to do stuff?", "qSentId": 302}, {"answer": "They have lost an institution, when these -- when these people leave us, they leave a hole that doesn't get filled.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 316, "question": "What do you think America has lost today?", "qSentId": 315}, {"answer": "Think I appreciate it now more than I did then, because back then, we were still very much kids.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 349, "question": "How big a moment is that for any musical act?", "qSentId": 348}, {"answer": "You know, the thing is that I remember one time we first met, he kept saying gentlemen, gentlemen to us, because -- say that to us.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 376, "question": "William, he says it all there, Lionel, doesn't it?", "qSentId": 375}, {"answer": "You know, I did realize.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 407, "question": "And did you realize at the time what a big deal it was?", "qSentId": 406}, {"answer": "I don't think it's a stretch at all.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 440, "question": "Is it a stretch to say that Dick Clark played a really significant and valuable role in the civil rights movement because of the way that he brought black performers and black bands and music to mainstream American television?", "qSentId": 439}, {"answer": "I think it is what the guys were saying, that he didn't put his own opinion -- he really represented the music that America loved and wanted to hear.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 464, "question": "What was it about him, do you think, that made him so universally popular?", "qSentId": 463}, {"answer": "He was sprinkling, you know, this magical dust of sorts across television with award shows and reality shows and game shows.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 507, "question": "He was really, as Larry King and others said earlier, pretty unique and pretty irreplaceable, wasn't he?", "qSentId": 506}, {"answer": "I think a lot of people in the television industry do feel like he's the closest.", "docId": "120418pmt", "aSentId": 519, "question": "Would you go along with that?", "qSentId": 518}]